Julie V Scher

www.julievscher.com hireme@julievscher.com behance.net/julievscher linkedin.com/in/julie-v-scher-a3905b223/ in 239•321•9752 \$\\ \end{align*}

UI/UX Designer | Behaviour Analyst

PROFILE

I am an artistic and analytical UI/UX designer and behaviour analyst. My knowledge of UI/UX methodologies, in combination with my deep understanding of the principles of human behaviour, allow me to create enjoyable digital experiences that keep users engaged.

EDUCATION



Ball State / MA Behaviour Analysis

SEPT 2012 - JUNE 2015, INDIANA

Awarded the Dean's Citation for Academic Excellence in recognition a perfect 4.0 GPA.



York University / BA Psychology

SEPT 2006 - JUNE 2009, TORONTO

Recipient of the Vanier Vingt-Deux Award: The Master's Honor Roll.



Ryerson University / BA Radio TV

SEPT 2000 – JUNE 2004, TORONTO

Among the top 15% of students at Ryerson University for academic achievement.

LICENSES AND CERTIFICATIONS



Board Certified Behaviour Analyst

MAY 2017- PRESENT



Foundations of User Experience (UX) Design

OCT 2021

Course 1 of the Google UX Design Professional Certificate



Visual Elements of User Interface Design

OCT 2021

California Institute of the Arts



Start the UX Design Process: Empathize, Define,

and Ideate

NOV 2021

Course 2 of the Google UX Design Professional Certificate

SKILLS

Design

Figma • Adobe XD • HTML5 • CSS3 • Github • Wireframing • Prototyping

Research

Data Analysis • Advanced Research Methods I&II • Advanced Statistics I& II • Quantitative & Qualitative Research • Attitudinal & behavioural approaches to identify user pain points

Personal

Self-starter • Empathetic • Reliable • Creative • Helpful

EXPERIENCE

Florida Autism Center / Center Director

FEB 2018 - OCT 2019, FLORIDA

Lead a team in facilitating optimal care and measurable positive outcomes for clients with autism. Reliably met tight deadlines and strict budgetary goals.

Speech Therapy Works / Behaviour Analyst

OCT 2017 - JAN 2018, TORONTO

Oversaw clinical team meetings and problem solved with a multidisciplinary team of professionals.

Above and Beyond Consulting Inc. / Instructor Therapist

SEPT 2015 - APRIL 2016, TORONTO

Collected and analyzed data to assess treatment effectiveness.

Under the Umbrella Tree Educational Services Inc. / Therapist

FEB 2014 - APRIL 2014, TORONTO

Interpreted and presented client data at clinical team meetings.

Blue Balloon Health Services / Instructor Therapist

NOV 2012 - JAN 2014, TORONTO

Wrote behaviour protocols to decrease problem behaviour and increase appropriate responses.